Guide to the John Kent Folmar's Collection on the Monongahela River Buffs Association, 1870-2015 AIS.2019.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, 1870-2005; IV.
  - Vessels and River Scenes, undated; 6.
    - J.D. Ayers, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - J.H. Hillman, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - J.H. McCrady, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - J.J. Cavett, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - J.L. Perry, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Jack Rathbone, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Jacob G., undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Jadwin, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - James E. Lose (Diesel Towboat), undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - James E. Lose (Steamboat), undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Jason, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Jim Brown, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Joe T., undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - John H. Elliott, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - John W. Hubbard, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Juniata, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Katie Lyons, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Kay H., undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Keystone, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Kinzua, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Kittanning, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Kongo, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - L.G. Beaver, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - L.M. Smith, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - L.W. Morgan, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Leona, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Little Bill, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Lunga Point, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Marcia Richardson, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Mark Winnett, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Mary Alice, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Mathies, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Maxwell Locks and Dam, Monongahela River Flood, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Maxwell Locks and Dam, Monongahela River Flood, January, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - McNeirney, John, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Miami, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Mildred, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Mon River Towing Inc. photo album, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Mongah, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Monitor, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Monongahela, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Monongahela River Flood, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Monongahela River Scenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Multiple Vessels, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Myra H., undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nancy Jane, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Nellie Hudson, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Neville, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nicholas Duncan, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Ohio River Ice Gorge, March, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Ohio River Scenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Olivette, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Onward, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Orleanian, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Parkersburg, West Virginia, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Patsy Hillman, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Peace, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Pennsylvania, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Pioneer, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh (Diesel Towboat), undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Pittsburgh (Steamboat), undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Pittsburgh Coal, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Flood, March, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Scenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Prosperity, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Ranger, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Reindeer, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Relief, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Rezistal, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Rhododendron Showboat, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Richard, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Rival, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - River Scenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Robert E. Reed, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Robert F. Brandt, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - "Romance of the Rivers" exhibit, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Rover, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - S.M. Jenks, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Sailor, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Sam Barnum, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Sam Brown, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Sam Craig, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Sam P. Suit, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Scout, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Seven Sons, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Sewickley, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Shannopin, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Shawnee, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Sprague, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Steamboat Races Pittsburgh, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Superior, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Tammy L. White, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Tanner, Jannette Hanna, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Taylor, undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Tell City, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Tennessee, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Thomas Moses, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Titan, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Tornado, undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Trojan, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Unidentified Diesel Towboat pushing a Commercial Barge Lines car barge, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified Diesel Towboats, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified man building a steamship model, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified man in wheelhouse, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified vessel, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - United States, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - USS Jenks, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - USS-1, October 18, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - USS-3, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Venice, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Vesta, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Virginia, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Volunteer, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Vulcan (Diesel Towboat), undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Vulcan (Steamboat), undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - W.C. Jutte, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - W.H. Colvin Jr., undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - W.J. Kearns, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - W.M. Rees, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - W.P. Snyder Jr., undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Warren Elsey, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Wheeling, West Virginia, Bridge over icy river and barge, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - William G. Clyde, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - William Wingham, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Winnie Mae, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Wm. B Rodgers, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Wm. C. Sutherland, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Wm. Larimer Jones, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Workers on Hillman Boats, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - William Dickie Photo Album, c.1930-2005; 7.
    Photo album with "Property of William Dickie" written inside the front and back cover. All photos are black and white and depict riverboats. Boats pictured include Becky Thatcher, C. Sutherland, Champion Coal, Charles Rock, Clairton, Clyde, Crucible, Delta Queen, Duquesne, E.K. Davison, Edgar Thomson, Homestead, James E. Lose, Juniata, Leona, Lone Star, Miss Sterling, Pansy, Prosperity, Rezistal, Sailor, Thomas Moses, Titan, Vesta, and W.P. Snyder Jr. There are also a few loose photographs of the sunken Clairton and the attempt to raise it as well a newspaper clipping of the sinking of the Elizabeth M and scans of other photographs that were tucked inside the front cover.
    - William Dickie photo album, c. 1930-2005 (Box 8, Volume 1)
  - William L. Hood Photographs and Negatives, c. 1930s-1950s; 8.
    Photographs and negatives believed to be taken by or of William L. Hood. The black and white photographs are inside of a cellophane envelope with "Billy Hood" written on it. They depict various scenes in Tennessee, Florida, and an unidentified Atlantic Ocean beach. Additionally, there is a small portrait with "William L. Hood" written on the back. The negatives are not of the same photographs. The negatives depict people, primarily children and an unidentified couple, along with an unidentified monument.
    - William L. Hood Negatives, c. 1950s (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - William L. Hood Photographs, c. 1930s (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Postcards, undated; V.
  This series consists of postcards that depict Pennsylvania and Monongahela River related scenes. Most were originally sorted by geographic location (although, sometimes it was broad, such as "PA Scenes"). In order to aid access, the postcards are now sorted alphabetically by the town they depict, regardless of state. In cases where a town is not listed, a different geographic or topical name is used.
  - Alexander Mackenzie steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Allegheny, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - American steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Arthur Hider steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - B.F. Fairless steamboat at Elizabeth, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Baton Rouge, Louisiana, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Beallsville, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Bellaire, Ohio, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Bentleyville, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Betsy Ann steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Brownsville, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - C.W. Talbot steamboat, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - California, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Canonsburg, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Centreville, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Charleroi, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cincinnati, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - City of Wheeling steamboat at Wheeling, West Virginia, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Donora, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Duquesne steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Eastern towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Edward J. Gay steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Elizabeth, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Excursion Queen Saint Paul steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Fairplay steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Franklin, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - G.A. Boeckling ferry, Cedar Point, Sandusky, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - G.W. McBride steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Galveston, Texas, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - General Wood steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Gordon C. Greene steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Henry C. Yeiser Jr. steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Homer Smith steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Homestead, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Iowa steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Irvin Works of Carnegie-Illinois Steel, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - J.B. Finley steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - J.D. Ayres steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - J.M. White steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Jack Rathbone steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Jason steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Johnstown, Pennsylvania Flood of 1889, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Joseph B. Williams steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Julius Fleischmann steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Lehigh towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Lewisburg, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Locks on the Ohio River, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Marietta, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - McKeesport, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Monitor steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Monongahela steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Monongahela, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Mount Dora, Florida, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Natchez steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Navigator towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - New Martinsville, West Virginia, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Omar steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Peace towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Pennsylvania scenes, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Pennsylvania Turnpike, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - President steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Queen City steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Rankin, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Reliance steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Reliance towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Robert E. Lee steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Robert F. Brandt steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Sailor steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Senator Cordill steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Shartlesville, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Slackwater steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Sprague steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Somerset, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Steamer Admiral at St. Louis, Missouri, undated (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Steamer Delta Queen steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Steamer Ohio at Pomeroy, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Steamer St. Paul at Alton, Illinois, undated (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Steubenville, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Swan steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - The Larry-Don Excursion Boat at Lake of the Ozarks, Missouri, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - The Sunny South Floating Theatre, undated (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Tom Rees No. 2 steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Troy, Ohio, undated (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Twilight steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Valley Forge, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Virginia steamboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Washington, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - West Alexander, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - West Newton, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Wm. Penn towboat, undated (Box 9, Folder 79)
- Realia, undated; VI.
  This series contains artifacts in the form of buttons from political campaigns, but it also includes a number of other types of buttons. Additionally, there is a flag from a J&L Steel ship.
  - Political Buttons, undated; 1.
    A collection of buttons, primarily for political campaigns. Political buttons are sorted by the type of race they were used in. Buttons for some presidential campaigns were separated into their own folders because there was a higher volume of buttons related to that particular person/campaign or the race is particularly notable, such as the Mondale-Ferrero race being the first major party ticket to feature a female Vice-Presidential candidate. Folders related to a specific campaign may include reproduction buttons. In addition to the political campaign buttons, there are other buttons which were sorted by theme.
    - Americanism, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Anti-Nuclear Power, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Anti-smoking and Pollution, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Athletic related, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Business Promotional Materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Congressional and Senatorial mixed, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "DALEY", undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Governor, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Labor Union related, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Military, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Novelty, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Operation "REACH" (Boy Scots of America), undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Mayor, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Peace and Unity related, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Penn State University, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Pennsylvania Attorney General, District Attorney, and Supreme Court, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania Legislation, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Presidential, Carter, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Presidential, Kennedy (John, Robert, and Ted), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Presidential, Mondale and Ferraro, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Presidential, Nixon (Campaigns and Impeachment), undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Presidential, Real, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Presidential, Reproductions, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Presidential, Wallace, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Restore Greene Academy", undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Shamrocks For Dystrophy", undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - United States Senate, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Voting related, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Water Safety, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Riverboat Artifacts, undated; 2.
    This subseries consists of one Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation flag. The flag is green and yellow and displays the J&L logo.
    - Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation flag, undated (Box Unknown)
- Record Books from Vessels, 1948-1972; VII.
  The first volume appears to be written descriptions of how to navigate various stretches of the Ohio River that was written aboard the Carnegie-Illinois Steel Company's Duquense steamboat in 1942. The second volume is a logbook from the Edgar Thomson steamboat from when the crew of the Duquense helped prepare the vessel to sail in February 1944 through the final entry on February 3, 1948. The third volume is a logbook for M.V. John H. Elliott, based on the stamp present on the first few pages. The logbook records its journey along the Monongahela River from February 6, 1967, to November 1, 1972.
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Co., Steamer, Duquesne, 1942 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Logbook, M.V. John H. Elliott, 1967-1972 (Oversize 12, Volume 2)
  - Logbook, Steamer Edgar Thomson, 1944-1948 (Oversize 12, Volume 3)
- Scrapbooks, 1936-2005; VIII.
  Seven scrapbooks containing photos and newspaper clippings of shipbuilders, riverboats, and sailors, primarily on the Monongahela River, as well as clippings related to the Monongahela River Buffs Association and its members. Additionally, there is another scrapbook that was disassembled into four separate folders.
  - Scrapbook, 1936 Pittsburgh Flood Scrapbook (Oversize 12, Volume 1)
    Scrapbook containing a few photographs and many newspaper clippings related to the March 1936 Pittsburgh flood, also known as The Great St. Patrick's Day flood.
  - Scrapbook, Canoe Voyage, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11-14)
    Scrapbook disassembled into four folder: Newspaper Clippings, Black & White Photographs, Color Photographs, and a Roster & Diary of the canoe trip down the Monongahela River on July 1-4, 1975. Originally, these materials were in a scrapbook, which has be disassembled. The trip was led by John Flower as a way to celebrate the bicentennial. The photographs consist of color and black and white shots of the canoe trip, including people dressing up as pioneers and Native Americans. The clippings are from local newspapers and also relate to the same trip.
  - Scrapbook, Clippings from Waterways Journal, St. Louis, Missouri, 1948-1950 (Oversize 13, Volume 2)
    Articles and photos clipped out of Waterways Journal. The date range of articles appears to be from 1948 to 1950, although some refer to events from twenty or forty years prior. Articles center around riverboats, shipbuilders, and people associated with both from various rivers in the Midwest.
  - Scrapbook, Diesel Towboats, undated (Oversize 12, Volume 3)
    Scrapbook containing photos of diesel towboats clipped out of publications. The main owners of the boats pictured are Hillman, Guidry Towing Co., as well as other companies primarily operating out of the Midwest. Pictured vessels include Aaron J. Toups, Arkansas Explorer, Bayou Boeuf, Betty Joyce, Capt. Sam, David P. Guidry, Dennis W. Guidry, E.A. Gonsoulin, Elaine Jones, Explorer, Exxon Kentucky, Gnots IX, Itasca, Lagonda, Lewiston, Pearl Bellinger, Presque Isle, R Paul Guidry, Robert Crown, and Sea Islander.
  - Scrapbook, Ernie Gabler's River Scrapbook, undated (Oversize 13, Volume 4)
    Newspaper and Voice of the Mon clippings related to the Monongahela River, Ernie "Weenie" Gabler building ship models, and the Monongahela River Buffs Association. Additionally, there are photos of Gabler, as well as postcards from Binghamton, New York, brochures for historical places in the Greensboro, Pennsylvania region, photocopies of newspaper articles and photographs, and nautical stickers. The bulk of the clippings are from 1979-1990. The other materials are mostly undated.
  - Scrapbook, Fortune Magazine Riverboat Clippings Scrapbook, c. 1948-1950 (Oversize 12, Volume 5)
    Newspaper clippings of steamboats, tug boats, and the Monongahela River pasted inside of a February 1947 copy of Fortune Magazine. Clippings are primarily from the late 1940s into the early 1950s. Inside the magazine itself, there is also an article entitled "Pittsburgh's New Power."
  - Scrapbook, Hendrickson Riverboat Photographs Scrapbook, undated (Oversize 14, Volume 6)
    Scrapbook containing photographs of riverboats and unidentified people, in addition to a few pieces of mail addressed to Mrs. Hendrickson (both "S.W." and "Ida M.") as well as a number of clippings featuring celebrities and pieces of advertisements. Pictured vessels include Aliquippa, Ashland, Atta Boy and the Majestic showboat, C.W. Talbot, Champion Coal, Charles R. Hook, Charles T. Campbell, Clairton, Commercial Clipper (Commercial Barge Lines Inc. car barge based out of Cincinnati, Ohio), Crescent, D.W. Wisherd, Delta Queen, E.D. Kenna, Ernest T. Weir, Esso Louisiana, Frank C. Rand, Gordon C. Greene, H.E. Lewis, Henry A. Laughlin, Island Queen, J.D. Ayres, Jefferson, Kenova, Louisiana, Mongah, O.F. Shearer, Omar, Patrick J. Hurley, Pittsburgh Coal, Renown, Robert F. Brandt, Sam P. Suit, Scioto, Taric, Thomas Moses, Tom Greene, Victory (Dravo), W.F. McCrady, W.H. Colvin Jr., W.P. Snyder Jr, Walter F. Carey, and Wm. B. Rodgers.
  - Scrapbook, Monongahela River towns and vessels Scrapbook, c. 1974-2005 (Oversize 14, Volume 7)
    Newspaper and Voice of the Mon clippings related to Greensboro's Bicentennial, New Geneva, Brownsville, ships and bridges on the Monongahela River, barges sinking, and the Edmund Fitzgerald sinking.
- The Voice of the Mon, 1979-2015; IX.
  Copies of The Voice of the Mon, the newsletter of the Monongahela Rivers Buffs Association. The newsletter was published from 1979 to 2015.
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 1, Issue 1-2, 4-12, 1979 (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 2, Issue 1-12, 1980 (Oversize 11, Folder 7)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 3, Issue 1-6, 1981 (Oversize 11, Folder 8)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 4, Issue 1-5, 1982 (Oversize 11, Folder 9)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 5, Issue 1-5, 1983 (Oversize 11, Folder 10)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 6, Issue 1-3, 1985 (Oversize 11, Folder 11)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 7, Issue 1-3, 1986 (Oversize 11, Folder 12)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 8, Issue 1-2, 1987 (Oversize 11, Folder 13)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 9, Issue 1, 1988 (Oversize 11, Folder 14)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 10, Issue 1-3, 1989 (Oversize 11, Folder 15)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 11, Issue 1-2, 1990 (Oversize 11, Folder 16)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 12, Issue 1-3, 1991 (Oversize 11, Folder 17)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 13, Issue 2, 1992 (Oversize 11, Folder 18)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 14, Issue 1-3, 1993 (Oversize 11, Folder 19)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 15, Issue 1-2, 1994 (Oversize 11, Folder 20)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 16, Issue 1, 1995 (Oversize 11, Folder 21)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 17, Issue 1-2, 1996 (Oversize 11, Folder 22)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 18, Issue 1, 1997 (Oversize 11, Folder 23)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 19, Issue 1, 2000 (Oversize 11, Folder 24)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 20, Issue 1, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 21, Issue 1-2, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 22, Issue 1-2, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 23, Issue 1-2, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 24, Issue 1-2, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 25, Issue 1-2, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 6)